## **Emin Inanc Unlu**

## Product Designer & Prototype Developer

MOBILE 0090 507 084 74 82

MAIL einancunlu@gmail.com

WEB einancunlu.github.io

ARTICLES medium.com/@einancunlu

Hello, I am a self-taught Product Designer with a degree in Computer Science and various coding experience. I love working on UI & UX and I always stay hungry for self-improvement.

Understanding the development side of the products makes me a better designer. It also helps a lot while working with the developers.

In my spare time, I like writing and sharing my knowledge on Medium, traveling the world, go for hiking, reading, watching, working on side projects and contributing to the community.

Some of my articles and Sketch plugins were featured on Sketch Newsletter, Designer News, Hey Designer and Indie iOS Dev Weekly.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

APR 2015 - PRESENT • REMOTE

### Freelance Product Designer — HelloTalk

HelloTalk is a language learning & exchange app with more than 6 million users worldwide. I worked on the redesign of the UI and on the new features.

SEP 2014 – FEB 2015 • PERSONAL PROJECT

## Languru — Universal iOS App

I made a dictionary app which is focused on using human translated example sentences for language learning. It supports more than 100 languages.

NOV 2013 - JUL 2014 • ANKARA, TURKEY

# iOS & Front-End Developer, UI Designer

- Korvus

I was involved in design and development of web and mobile parts of a social advertising project.

FEB 2013 – JUN 2013 • PERSONAL PROJECTS

Finimalist and TOBB ETU — iPhone Apps

SEP 2012 - DEC 2012 • INTERNSHIP • ANKARA, TURKEY

**Graphic Designer** — Expokent

JAN 2011 – APR 2011 • INTERNSHIP • ESKISEHIR, TURKEY

Android Developer, UI Designer — Ester



#### **EDUCATION**

2008 - 2013 • FULL SCHOLARSHIP

Computer Engineering — GPA: 3.3 out of 4.0

TOBB University of Economics and Technology



#### **LANGUAGES**

English — Professional Proficiency

TOEFL IBT Score: 80 / 120 — February 2014 (Outdated)

Turkish — Native

German and Spanish — Beginner

Mobile Design Prototyping Interaction, Icon Design

Web, Desktop Design Photography Motion Design

Illustration
3D and Print Design

Swift, Objective-C HTML, CSS, JSON FramerJS, Coffeescript

SASS, LESS, Cocoascript Javascript, JQuary Foundation, Bootstrap

Java, Android XML, SQLite Mac OS, Sketch, Framer Noodl, Origami Studio Xcode, Slack, Screenflow

Trello, Zeplin, Invision Pixelmator, Motion 5 Figma, Coda, Git

Photoshop, Blender Affinity Designer